Guide to the Rice University Bands (MOB) records, 1914-2012 UA 239
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Bands (MOB) records
1914-2011
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 239
23.5 Linear Feet (30 Boxes)
This collection consists of correspondence, financial information, newsletters, newsclippings, photographs, recordings, memorabilia, and uniforms related to Rice University Bands, including MOB, Rice Jazz Ensemble, and Rice Concert Band.
Biographical/Historical Note
Forming in 1916, the Rice Owl Band consisted of twelve members with interests in band activities and reading band literature. By 1922, when Lee Chatham became the director, the band had 35 members and grew to 50 under his leadership. Since there was a dearth of high school bands, some of the members came from the community at large.
During World War II, the membership of the band was unstable, which lead to the creation of a new band of Navy cadets under the V-12 program. After the war, the band reorganized and the all-male outfit added four majorettes.
In the 1950s and 1960s, director Holmes McNeely made the band co-ed, bought instruments, added personnel, and gave a small number of band scholarships. The issuing of scholarships continued under director Bert Roth (1967-1979) who provided work scholarships for participating band members. Roth also changed the focus of the band from a marching band to a scatter band.
Starting in 1970, the band began to infuse timely and sometimes controversial topics into their halftime shows. Into the 1970s, the band began to move away from traditional band uniforms and sometimes chose outfits that matched the theme of their halftime shows.
1980 brought Ken Dye as the new Rice Owl Band director. He added new bands like the Jazz Ensemble and the Rice Concert Band. In addition, he selected the mob-style uniforms to match the new name of the band, the Marching Owl Band (MOB). Dyer also promoted travel, even taking the MOB to the Opening Ceremonies of the 1984 Olympics, the 1986 Statue of Liberty celebration, the 1986 U.S. Olympic Festival, and 1993 Carnivale in Nice, France.
Currently, band director Chuck Throckmorton has continued the legacy of Ken Dye. The Jazz Ensemble, Basketball Owl Band, Rice Symphonic Band, and Houston Concert Band continue to provide an outlet for non-music majors at Rice. Meanwhile, the MOB still plays halftime shows and courts controversy.
--Taken from "The MOB: Rice University Owl Marching Owl Band" handbook, 1988.
Scope and Contents Note
This collection consists of materials related to the Rice Owl Band, Jazz Ensemble, Rice Symphonic Band, and Marching Owl Band (MOB). This includes annual reports, correspondence, financial information, handbooks, newsletters, scripts, newsclippings, performances, photographs, recordings, memorabilia, and uniforms.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Accruals Note
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Rice University -- History; Music
Document Types
uniforms; photographs
Subjects (Persons)
Roth, Bert
- Series I: Advertising, n.d., 162033
  - The Rice Thresher, n.d.; 162034 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rice Bands and MOB, 162035 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Annual Reports, 1999-2004, 162036
  - Rice University Bands Annual Report, 1999-2000; 145563 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rice University Bands Annual Report, 2000-2001; 145564 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rice University Bands Annual Report, 2001-2002; 145565 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student Affairs Annual Report, 2001-2002; 145566 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rice University Bands Annual Report, 2002-2003; 162038 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rice University Bands Annual Report, 2003-2004; 162039 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series III: Banquets and Awards, 1983-2010, 162040
  - MOB Banquet, 1983; 162041 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Awards, 1983; 162042 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - MOB Banquet, 1984-1986; 162043 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - MOB Awards, 1993-1994; 162044 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MOB Attendance Award Certificate, 1997; 162045 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Midyear Banquet, 2009-2010; 162046 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Calendars, 1983-2001, 162047
  - 1983, 2000-2001, 162050 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rice Owls Football Schedule, 1993; 162048 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Owls Football Schedule, 1994; 162049 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Women's Basketball schedule, 2000-2001; 162311 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series V: Correspondence, 1950s-2009, 162051
  - General, 1950s; 162052 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - General, 1970-1979; 162053 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - General, 1980-1989; 162054 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Memoranda, 1983; 162055 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - MOB Orientation Week, 1983; 162056 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Recruitment, 1983; 162057 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Memoranda, 1984; 162058 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - General, 1990-1999; 162059 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Addresses, 1992-1993; 162060 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General, 2000-2009; 162061 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Rice Bands interest cards, 162062 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series VI: Courses, 1983-2004, 162063
  - Band Arranging - Music 415b, 1983; 162064 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Summer Camp information, 1989-2004; 162065 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Arts Administration Concentration, 1990; 162066 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Series VII: Financial, 1982-2002, 162067
  - Budget, 1982-1983; 162068 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Purchase orders, 1983; 162069 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Administrative supplies, 1983-1984; 162070 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Basketball scholarships, 1983-1984; 162071 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bookstore sales, 1983-1984; 162077 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Budget, 1983-1984; 162078 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Check request forms, 1983-1984; 162079 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Entertainment expense statement, 1983-1984; 162080 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Interdepartmental charges, 1983-1984; 162081 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Mail room charges, 1983-1984; 162082 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Mileage voucher, 1983-1984; 162083 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Petty cash, 1983-1984; 162084 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Printing, 1983-1984; 162085 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Travel expenses, 1983-1984; 162086 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Administrative supplies, 1984-1985; 162087 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Campus store, 1984-1985; 162088 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Check requests, 1984-1985; 162089 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Entertainment expenses, 1984-1985; 162090 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Interdepartmental charges, 1984-1985; 162091 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Invoices, 1984-1985; 162092 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mail room charges, 1984-1985; 162093 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mileage voucher, 1984-1985; 162094 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Petty cash, 1984-1985; 162095 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Printing, 1984-1985; 162096 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Purchase orders, 1984-1985; 162097 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Travel expenses, 1984-1985; 162098 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Administrative supplies, 1985-1986; 162099 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Campus store, 1985-1986; 162100 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Check requests and comptroller memos, 1985-1986; 162101 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Entertainment expenses, 1985-1986; 162102 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Interdepartmental charges, 1985-1986; 162103 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mail room charges, 1985-1986; 162104 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Petty cash, 1985-1986; 162105 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Travel expenses, 1985-1986; 162106 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sack lunches, 1994; 162107 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Music stands, 1995; 162108 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Yamaha percussion, 2001; 162109 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Trostan Printing, 2002; 162110 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Series VIII: Governance, 2001, 162111
  - MOB staff leadership training, 2001; 162112 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Band operations and facilities managers, 162113 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series IX: Handbooks, 1969-2001, 162114
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1969-1970; 162115 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1971-1972; 162116 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1972-1973; 162118 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1973-1974; 162119 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1974-1975; 162120 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1976-1977; 162121 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1977-1978; 162122 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1978-1979; 162123 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - The Owl Band of Rice University, 1979-1980; 162124 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - The MOB - Rice University Marching Owl Band, 1980s; 162126 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Rice Football, 1983; 162127 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Southwest Conference Football Souvenir Yearbook, 1984; 162128 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - The MOB - Rice University Marching Owl Band, 1988; 162129 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Rice Owls Basketball, 2001; 162130 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Rice Band Directory, 162131 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Series X: Instruments, 1979-2003, 162132
  - Clarinet inventory, 1979; 162133 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Double reed inventory, 1979; 162134 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Flute inventory, 1979; 162135 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - French horn inventory, 1979; 162136 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Saxophone inventory, 1979; 162137 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Trumpet inventory, 1979; 162138 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Contract, 1984; 162139 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Storage rental, 1999-2002; 162140 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Stolen Rice Band instruments, 2003; 162141 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Baritone inventory, n.d.; 162142 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Bass inventory, n.d.; 162143 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Percussion inventory, n.d.; 162144 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Trombone inventory, n.d.; 162145 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Series XI: Jazz and Symphonic Bands, 1983-1995, 162146
  - Jazz Band/MOB Concert, November 3, 1983; 162147 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Jazz Ensemble Concert, November 30, 1983; 162148 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Jazz Band, 1983-1984; 162149 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Jazz Band mailing list, 1983-1984; 162150 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Jazz Band roster, 1983-1984; 162151 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Rice Concert Band and Jazz Ensemble Concert, February 29, 1984; 162152 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Rice Concert Band and Jazz Ensemble Concert, April 12, 1984; 162153 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Foley's All-Star Band application, 1993-1994; 162154 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Rice Symphonic Band, 1994; 162155 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Grammy All-Star Jazz Band, 1995; 162156 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Rice Symphonic Band roster, Spring 1995; 162157 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Series XII: Meetings, 1983-1984, 162158
  - Notes, 1983-1984; 162159 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Series XIII: MOB Newsletters/Handouts, 1980-1999, 162160
  - 1980-1989, 162161 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1990-1999, 162162 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - New Band Hall dedication speech, 2017-03 (Box 3, Folder 2a)
- Series XIV: Music, 1925, n.d., 162163
  - "Put on Your Old Grey Bonnet" (scanned copy), 1925; 162164 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Fight Song", n.d.; 162165 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - MOB List of songs, n.d.; 162166 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Scripts, n.d.; 162167 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series XV: News Clippings, 1914-2010, 145539
  - 1914-1929, 145540 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1930-1939, 145541 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1940-1949, 145542 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1950-1959, 145543 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1960-1969, 145544 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1970-1979, 162168 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Rice v. Texas A&M (Halftime of Infamy), 1973; 145545 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1980-1989, 145546 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1990-1999, 145547 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 2000-2009, 145549 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 2010-, 162170 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - n.d., 162171 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Series XVI: Performances, 1968-2004, 162172
  General Note
  This series includes information about performances, such as programs and correspondence.
  - Fliers, 1968-1998; 162173 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Inauguration of Norman Hackerman, 1971; 162174 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - University of Houston Show, 1975; 162175 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Rice Band Concert at Sam Houston Park, 1976; 162176 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Jazz Festival, March 1983; 162177 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Southern Methodist University, 1983; 162178 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Tickets used, November 18, 1983; 162179 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Houston Festival, 1984; 162180 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Baylor University, 1984; 162181 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Bluebonnet Bowl Heritage Festival, December 1984; 162182 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Bluebonnet Bowl, 1986; 162183 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Suncoast Dome Opening, March 1990; 162184 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Whataburger All Star Band, 1991; 162185 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Texas All Stars - St. Patrick's Day Parade, Ireland, 1993; 162186 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Texas Trombones, 1993-1994; 162187 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - A Big Band Bash Program, 1994; 162188 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Charter Confirmation to Galveston Mardi Gras Parade, 1995; 162189 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Saks Fifth Avenue Opening, 1997; 162190 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Houston Parade, 2000; 162191 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - MOB Trip Policy, 2000-2003; 162192 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Galveston Mardi Gras Parade, February 24, 2001; 162193 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - St. Stephen's "Barefoot in the Park", 2001; 162194 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Parade, 2003; 162195 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - FIRST Robotics Competition, 2003; 162196 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - MOB trip policy forms, 2003-2004; 162197 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - President's Study Break, 2004; 162198 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Campus maps, n.d.; 162199 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Flow charts, n.d.; 162200 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Houston Rockets Victory Parade, n.d.; 162201 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - MOB event maps, n.d.; 162202 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Television opportunities, n.d.; 162203 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - University of Texas, n.d.; 162204 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Series XVII: Rosters, 1983-1994, 162205
  - Basketball Owl Band attendance, 1983-1984; 162206 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Houston Concert Band roster, 1993-1994; 162207 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - MOB roster, 1994; 162208 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Chaperone lists, n.d.; 162209 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Series XVIII: Uniforms, 1969-2008, 162210
  - Correspondence, 1969-1999; 162211 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Stanbury, 1981-1983; 162212 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Sale of old uniforms, 1982, 1999; 162213 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Group meeting, 1982; 162214 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Raincoats, 1982; 162215 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - New uniforms information, 1982; 162216 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Hats, 1983; 162217 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Receipts, 1983; 162218 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Checklist, 1991-1994; 162219 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Texas Bowl patch, 2008; 162220 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Series XIX: US Olympic Festival Band, 1986, 145697
  - Alternates, 1986; 145729 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Baritone Applications, 1986; 145720 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Bartner, Arthur, 1986; 145706 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Color Guard, 1986; 145726 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Constultant expenses, 1986; 145707 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Consultant invoices, 1986; 145714 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence, January 1986 - July 1986; 145715 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to band members, 1986; 145716 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Danny Ward Entertainment, 1986; 145704 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Directory, 1986; 162247 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Drill Team, 1986; 145728 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Drill Team uniforms, 1986; 145727 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - French horn applications, 1986; 145719 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gymnasts listing, 1986; 145700 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Invoices, 1986; 162248 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mastandrea, Donna, 1986; 145705 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Opening Ceremonies emblems, 1986; 145699 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Opening Ceremonies equipment, 1986; 145710 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Opening Ceremonies office equipment, 1986; 145712 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Opening Ceremonies outline, 1986; 162249 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Opening Ceremonies production advance report, 1986; 145701 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Orientation meetings, 1986; 162250 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Percussion alternates, 1986; 145724 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Percussion applications, 1986; 145723 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Percussion San Marcos trip, 1986; 145722 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Production expense advances, 1986; 145702 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Purchase orders received, 1986; 145709 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Rehearsal meals, 1986; 145713 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Robert Keith and Co. - Statue of Liberty inflatable, 1986; 145708 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Travel arrangements, 1986; 145703 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Trombone applications, 1986; 145717 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Trumpet applications, 1986; 145718 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Tuba applications, 1986; 145721 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Yamaha International, 1986; 145711 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Series XX: Slides and Photographs, 1968-2000s, 162252
  - Football, 1968; 162254 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Fifth Annual Band Day, September 17, 1960; 162255 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Band Banquet (1 of 2), 1967-1968; 162256 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Band Banquet (2 of 2), 1967-1968; 162257 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Football, 1968; 162258 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Mardi Gras Parade, New Orleans (1 of 2), 1968; 162259 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Mardi Gras Parade, New Orleans (2 of 2), 1968; 162260 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Football, 1969; 162261 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Football, 1960s-1970s; 162262 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Football, 1970; 162263 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Football, 1971; 162264 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Football, 1972; 162265 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rehearsal, 1972; 162266 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Football (1 of 4), 1974; 162267 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Football (2 of 4), 1974; 162268 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Football (3 of 4), 1974; 162269 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Football (4 of 4), 1974; 162270 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Basketball, 1975; 162271 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Concert Band, Sam Houston Park, 1975; 162272 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Football, 1975; 162273 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Bicycle Show, 1976; 162274 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Football, 1976; 162275 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Football, 1970s; 162276 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Owl Tails Uniform (negatives), 1970s; 162277 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Football/Basketball, 1980s-1990s; 162278 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Football (1 of 2), 1994; 162279 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Football (2 of 2), 1994; 162280 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Astrodome performance, September 16, 1991; 162281 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - MOB, 1994; 162282 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Texas A&M Pep Rally, October 1994; 162283 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Washington, D.C., 1994; 162284 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - MOB Staff and O-Week, 1995; 162285 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Football, 2002; 162286 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Football, 2004; 162287 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Football and MOB, 2000s; 162288 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Series XXI: Oversize Materials, 2000, n.d., 162308
  - Governor's Distinguished Collegiate Concert Band Award, April 8, 2000; 162309 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Rice Band sign, 162310 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Series XXII: Audio/Visual, 1980-1991, 146007
  - Subseries A: 7 inch reel, 162289
    - Rice Jazz Ensemble, October 27, 1982; 146008 (Box 6, Item 1)
    - Cardinal Jazz Festival at Lamar University, March 25, 1983; 146020 (Box 6, Item 2)
    - Rice Jazz Ensemble and Concert Band, April 19, 1983; 146013 (Box 6, Item 3)
    - Rice Concert Band and Jazz Ensemble Concert, April 13, 1988; 146011 (Box 6, Item 4)
    - Rice Jazz Ensemble, n.d.; 146012 (Box 6, Item 5)
    - Rice Jazz Ensemble and the Rice Concert Band, 146010 (Box 6, Item 6)
  - Subseries B: 10.5 inch reel, 162292
    - Rice University Jazz Ensemble, October 29, 1980; 146025 (Box 6, Item 7)
    - MOB, 1981; 146022 (Box 6, Item 8)
    - Rice Jazz Ensemble and Rice Concert Band, April 22, 1982; 146030 (Box 6, Item 9)
    - MOB Repertoire, Baylor University, November 13, 1982; 146032 (Box 6, Item 10)
    - Rice University Bands- Side "A", December 16, 1982; 146016 (Box 6, Item 11)
    - Rice University Bands- Side "B", December 16, 1982; 146017 (Box 6, Item 12)
    - MOB, October 25, 1983; 146031 (Box 7, Item 1)
    - MOB, October 25, 1983; 146023 (Box 7, Item 2)
    - First Session, October 21, 1986; 146021 (Box 7, Item 3)
    - Rice University Jazz Band, December 4, 1986; 146024 (Box 7, Item 4)
    - La Bamba, November 5, 1987; 146019 (Box 7, Item 5)
    - Rice Concert Band and Jazz Ensemble, February 25, 1988; 146027 (Box 7, Item 6)
    - MOB, Side I, 1990; 146014 (Box 7, Item 7)
    - MOB, Side II, 1990; 146015 (Box 7, Item 8)
    - Side "A", n.d.; 162296 (Box 7, Item 9)
    - Side "B", n.d.; 162297 (Box 7, Item 10)
    - Paul Williamson, n.d.; 162298 (Box 7, Item 11)
    - Unknown [MOB Side A or Master Reel?], [December 13, 1984 or November 1, 1985?]; 162295 (Box 8, Item 1)
    - Unknown [MOB Side B or Rice University Jazz Band?], [November 1, 1985?]; 162294 (Box 8, Item 2)
  - Subseries C: Cassette Tape, 162290
    - Rice Concert Band, 02/20/1991; 146035 (Box 8, Item 3)
    - Rice Concert Band and Jazz Ensemble, 02/20/1991; 146034 (Box 8, Item 4)
    - Rice Concert Band and Jazz Ensemble, 04/10/1991; 146036 (Box 8, Item 5)
    - Rice Concert Band and Jazz Ensemble, 04/10/1991; 146033 (Box 8, Item 6)
    - MOB Rock, 146037 (Box 8, Item 7)
    - Texas T-Bones, 146038 (Box 8, Item 8)
  - Subseries D: CD, 162291
    - Bob Files - Marching Owl Band, 148515 (Box 8, Item 9)
  - Subseries E: VHS, 162293
    - MOB, 1987; 162301 (Box 8, Item 10)
    - Sports Team Houston - "The MOB", December 4, 1988; 162302 (Box 8, Item 11)
    - MOB, 1988; 162299 (Box 8, Item 12)
    - MOB, 1989; 162303 (Box 8, Item 13)
    - Rice University Bands, c. 1989; 162300 (Box 8, Item 14)
    - MOB, 1990; 162304 (Box 8, Item 15)
    - MOB, 1990; 162305 (Box 8, Item 16)
    - MOB - "All the Shows None of the Commercials", 1991; 162306 (Box 8, Item 17)
    - MOB - "All the Shows None of the Commercials", 1991; 162307 (Box 8, Item 18)
  - Subseries F: DVD, 174982
    - Rice vs. University of Texas - MOB performance, October 4, 1980; 174983 (Box 8, Item 19)
- Series XXIII: Memorabilia, 1927-1984, 146039
  - Eagle Trophy - Band-Rally Club Annual Football Game, 1930-1933; 146040 (Box 9)
  - KPRC Second Place Trophy - Houston Recreational Department, 1930-05-07 (Box 9a)
  - Chronicle Jubilee Parade trophy, 1935-04-08 (Box 9a)
  - Rice Institute Band Montgomery Award - Robert S. Alcott, 1948-1949; 146041 (Box 10)
  - O.O. Hill Music Co. Houston Rec. Department Band and Orchestra Contest - First Prize Rice Institute Band, May 15, 1931; 146042 (Box 11)
  - Harris County Band and Orchestra Contest - Auspices Recreation Dept. Goggan Award, May 5, 1927; 146043 (Box 11)
  - Trombone, 146044 (Box 12)
  - Album - Rice University Presents The mob... and the Jazz Ensemble, 1984; 184960 (Box 14)
- Series XXIV: Uniforms, 1921-1990s, 146045
  - Owl Tail Hat, c. 1970s; 146046 (Box 13)
  - Owl Tail Hat, c. 1970s; 146047 (Box 13)
  - Owl Tail Hat, c. 1970s; 146048 (Box 14)
  - Owl Tail Hat, c.1970s; 146049 (Box 14)
  - Band Hat, c. 1921; 146050 (Box 15)
  - MOB Gray Felt Fedora, 1997; 146051 (Box 15)
  - Band Uniform Jacket with Braiding on the Shoulder, c. 1950; 146052 (Box 16)
  - Band Uniform jacket with tails and pants, early 1970s; 164507 (Box 17)
  - Blue Drum Major hat, early 1970s; 164508 (Box 18)
  - White Drum Major hat with blue and orange feather plumes, 1970s; 164823 (Box 19)
  - Drum Major baton with red rope, 1970s; 164824 (Box 20)
  - Denim outfit, including vest, shirt, and patch hat, 1976-1981 (Box 21)
  - Black leather belt, 1970s (Box 21)
  - Black lather instrument strap, 1970s (Box 21)
  - Military-style band hat - blue, 1960s-1970s (Box 21)
  - Military-style band hat - navy blue, 1960s-1970s (Box 21)
  - Silver plume for hat, 1930s-1970s (Box 21)
  - Band sweater from W. B. Chenault, Jr., 1937 (Box 21)
  - Tall white furry hat, n.d. (Box 22)